



<u>josh-atwal.com</u>

josh.atwal@outlook.com

Josh Atwal

Data Scientist & Software Engineer

In 8+ years of industry experience I have been thrown into countless unfamiliar situations and risen to the challenge every single time. By combining research and execution I've cultivated a talent for quickly navigating unfamiliar landscapes and solving any problem that I'm given.

For my next role, I'm looking to continue learning and challenging myself, with a particular interest in roles that involve data science, AI, and building software.

In my spare time I frantically keep up with the latest in AI and consume many books/podcasts on technology, philosophy, and psychology. I have too many hobbies; including hiking, bouldering, marathon running, and producing/DJing electronic music.

Recent Experience

CLOUD ENGINEER Amazon Web Services | 2024-Now

- Working within a team as a software engineer developing LLM agents to handle AWS support cases.
- SME-level knowledge of services and use-cases, such as model training and deployment, MLOps, and LLM knowledge bases + agents.
- Provide support and expertise to AWS customers using AI/ML services such as SageMaker and Bedrock.
- Involved in delivering training, mentoring, interviewing, and managing/delivering various projects from proof-of-concept to production

DATA SCIENTIST Y CoffeeAl | 2021-2023

- Backend Python developer/data scientist with other roles/responsibilities including system architect, devops, cloud infrastructure, DB admin.
- Relied upon to independently solve difficult engineering problems. Worked as part of a development team and managed interns.
- Built an entire SaaS product from the ground up.

MASTERS STUDENT Luma Analytics | 2021

- Self-directed exploratory research with minimal supervision - using data to uncover trends and improve the analytics and insights available for amateur golfers
- Involved PCA, clustering, data visualisation, web scraping.

COMPUTER VISION ENGINEER Beca | 2020-21

- An end-to-end computer vision solution encompassing data labelling, model training, and prediction validation.
- Researched contemporary computer vision models before implementing Faster-RCNN and YOLOv5 in PyTorch, tuning them to the dataset, and comparing their performance.
- Acted as Product Owner and team leader, self-directing the project with minimal supervision.

RESEARCH ASSISTANT Auckland Bioengineering Institute

- Ran experiments on a HPC cluster modelling signal propagation, visualised and presented the results
- Published author in JACC 2018

Education

Masters in Data Science

- University of Auckland 2020-2021
- First Class Honours

Bachelor of Engineering (Hons.) + Bachelor of Science

- University of Auckland 2015-2019
- First Class Honours

Technical Skills

- Data Science, Machine Learning, Statistics
- Software development in Python
- AWS (SageMaker, Bedrock, Lambda, and many other services)
- SQL and database administration
- · Team and project management